<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>nothing special</title>
 <link href="http://a.aronott.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://a.aronott.com"/>
 <updated>2013-01-13T18:40:37-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://a.aronott.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Aaron Ott</name>
   <email>aaron.ott@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Securing ownership of Drupal filesystem.</title>
   <link href="http://a.aronott.com/drupal/securing-ownership-of-drupal-filesystem"/>
   <updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://a.aronott.com/drupal/securing-ownership-of-drupal-filesystem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There was a security vulnerability found in Drupal 7.0 - 7.15 where a Drupal site could be hijacked given the wrong permissions to the settings.php file. Read more about it here &lt;a href='http://drupal.org/node/1815912'&gt;http://drupal.org/node/1815912&lt;/a&gt; if you are still running Drupal 7.15 or less, upgrade is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability relies on the settings.php file being writable by the web server. One way to ensure that these types of vulnerabilities don&amp;#8217;t effect your site is to set proper permissions to your install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my server, I will normally create a dev group and assign myself and other developers to that group. Then I set the permissions as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with all files :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown -R nobody:dev /path/to/drupal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set the owner to all files to nobody. This is a special user in linux and will ensure that no unnecessary permissions are granted to any of the files in the Drupal install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we set directory and file permissions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// start with the files
sudo chmod -R 664 /path/to/drupal
// now set the directories
sudo find /path/to/drupal -type d -exec chmod 775 {} \;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few final touches to make sure Drupal is happy with how things are set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// set the sites/default/files directory ownership
// www-data is the owner on most debian based systems,
// if you use a redhat based distro, you may need to set 
// the owner to &amp;#39;apache&amp;#39;
sudo chown -R www-data /path/to/drupal/sites/default/files&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just for a bit more security let&amp;#8217;s make the settings.php file read-only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod 444 /path/to/drupal/sites/default/settings.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should do it, permissions should now be set such that anyone in the dev group will be able modify files as needed for development purposes but the webserver will not have permission to modify files leaving the install a bit more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole script can be be downloaded &lt;a href='https://gist.github.com/3908003'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Library</title>
   <link href="http://a.aronott.com/the-library"/>
   <updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://a.aronott.com/the-library</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;#8217;m at one of my favorite places to be. Though not this particular branch but the Library is one of the greatest places there is. I feel saddened at the prospect that buildings such as this may be extinct in the future and feel that there is hope for these places as well. For the most part, many of the libraries have adapted to the times in allowing for free wifi access to any of its patrons and quite a bit of good quite sitting space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love reading but don&amp;#8217;t read many tree books any longer, most books that I read are the digital version unless I need it for reference. I don&amp;#8217;t use the library as a place to checkout books but more as a place to get things done. At the library you are free to sit without the distraction of cleaning the dishes or that other project around the house that has been sitting rotting to get done. The feeling is liberating really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sit here for about 3hrs today and am able to work on a few digital projects that I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to get to but have been a bit distracted at home. One of the projects is this page actually so I&amp;#8217;m not wasting any time by writing this up right quick. I&amp;#8217;m still learning this &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com/'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; thing but am really enjoying each step. With that, it&amp;#8217;s time to get at it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DBUG Meetup Notes</title>
   <link href="http://a.aronott.com/DBUG/dbug-meetup-notes"/>
   <updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://a.aronott.com/DBUG/dbug-meetup-notes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='date_20130109'&gt;Date 2013-01-09&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id='favorite_modules'&gt;Favorite modules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commerce attributes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Module filter&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Taxonomy roles&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Services module&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Examples module&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Live Reload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='topic_javascript_in_drupal'&gt;Topic: JavaScript in Drupal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Garrett (killtheliterate)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RequireJS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizing project in reusable modules is very important. Not seen as much in Drupal with JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javascript module Things are wrapped in a function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript Module can return something back to the Global Namespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://briancray.com/posts/javascript-module-pattern'&gt;http://briancray.com/posts/javascript-module-pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.adequatelygood.com/2010/3/JavaScript-Module-Pattern-in-Depth'&gt;http://www.adequatelygood.com/2010/3/JavaScript-Module-Pattern-in-Depth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id='asynchronous_module_definition'&gt;Asynchronous Module Definition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t polute the global namespace Javascript loads synchronously which can lead to slower loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drupal has an issue here, you would need to print out the javascript array and re-weight scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debugging becomes easier when modularizing code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AMD Links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/amdjs/amdjs-api/wiki/AMD'&gt;https://github.com/amdjs/amdjs-api/wiki/AMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.adequatelygood.com/2010/3/JavaScript-Module-Pattern-in-Depth'&gt;http://www.adequatelygood.com/2010/3/JavaScript-Module-Pattern-in-Depth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AMD is a method not a library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have an AMD module you need to be able to load it. RequireJS helps you do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RequireJS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourages modulalr code&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;encourages file organization&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;leverages AMD&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Offers optimization tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rjs - RequireJS optimization tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='requirejs__drupal'&gt;RequireJS &amp;amp; Drupal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RequireJS is a bit tougher to get into Drupal but it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple threads around adding the JavaScript to Drupal but there isn&amp;#8217;t a large backing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='open_discussion_happens'&gt;Open discussion happens&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>